Finding aid to Alumnae Oral History Project collection CA.MS.00301
Smith College Archives
- Alumnae Oral History Project interviews (2016), Accession 2016-A-0025
  - Mary Marcell (Class of 1986) interviewed by Sonia Lawrence, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Mary Marcell reflects on the social and political scenes on campus. Marcell remembers the relationship between Park and Hover House, as well as a campus wide emphasis on raising the visibility of issues affecting marginalized groups on campus.
    - Video interview with Mary Marcell
    - Transcript of interview with Mary Marcell (Box 14)
  - Ellen Moorhouse (Class of 1966) interviewed by Sonia Lawrence, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Ellen Moorhouse reflects on her transition to Smith as a Canadian international student. She remembers her community in Martha Wilson House and Dawes House. Moorhouse also talks about her idea of a "typical Smithie" and women's role in the workplace in the 60s.
    - Video interview with Ellen Moorhouse
    - Transcript of interview with Ellen Moorhouse (Box 14)
  - Felicia Otchet (Class of 1991) interviewed by Sunny Lawrence, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Felicia Otchet reflects on her time at Smith as a head resident, the psychology major, and Smith's vast recreational sports offerings. She talks about the campus' strong feminist and activist leanings, both in and out of class, highlighting the student's anti-racism protests in Lilly Hall. Since graduating Otchet remains focused on championing the underserviced, a trait she attributes to the lessons she learned at Smith.
    - Video interview with Felicia Otchet
    - Transcript of interview with Felicia Otchet (Box 14)
  - Elizabeth Zacharias Owens (Class of 2001) interviewed by Milada Cook, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In her interview, Lizzie Owens remembers the exploits of Capen house, full of the parties, and pranks, and an indelible community. A transfer student, Owens also focuses on her time in the history department, including a class trip to Russia. Owens also highlights the Smith alumnae network in helping to find connections and friendships in her life post-graduation.
    - Video interview with Elizabeth Zacharias Owens
    - Transcript of interview with Elizabeth Zacharias Owens (Box 14)
  - Sarah Perkins (Class of 2011) interviewed by Milada Cook, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Sarah Perkins, an Economics Major, talks about taking classes in the Five College Consortium, and finding community at Smith. Perkins was a member of the Smith Republican and Libertarian Club, as well as the Black Student Union, and the Christian fellowship.
    - Video interview with Sarah Perkins
    - Transcript of interview with Sarah Perkins (Box 14)
  - Sylvia Berman Perlman (Class of 1966) interviewed by Milada Cook, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Sylvia Perlman talks about her time in Talbot and Cutter House, Ivy Day traditions, and formal house dinners. A member of The Sophian and Hillel, Perlman remembers her time in each community, as well as her work in the Sociology department.
    - Video interview with Sylvia Berman Perlman
    - Transcript of interview with Sylvia Berman Perlman (Box 14)
  - Ryan Rasdall (Class of 2011) interviewed by Sonia Lawrence, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Ryan Rasdall looks back on his choice to attend Smith and the community he found in Wilder House. Rasdall, a Study of Women and Gender Studies Major, talks about the impact the newly formed department had on him. Rasdall also talks about the atmosphere on campus leading up to the 2008 election of President Obama.
    - Video interview with Ryan Rasdall
    - Transcript of interview with Ryan Rasdall (Box 14)
  - Katherine Reymann (Class of 1996) interviewed by Sonia Lawrence, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Katherine Reymann, former member of Emerson House and the Smith College Crew Team, looks back on her time in both communities, as well as the close friendships she formed there. Reymann remembers the social dynamics and tensions between the quad and the rest of campus, and the rise of activism in quad houses in support of minority students.
    - Video interview with Katherine Reymann
    - Transcript of interview with Katherine Reymann (Box 14)
  - Gretchen Freiheir Ridgeway (Class of 1966) interviewed by Rebecca York, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Gretchen Ridgeway reflects on the traditions of Hubbard House, where she lived for three years. She describes the roles that the house mother and house professor played in student's daily lives, providing among many other things emotional support and good dinner conversation. Ridgeway also talks about the merits of Smith's study-abroad programs.
    - Video interview with Gretchen Freiheir Ridgeway
    - Transcript of interview with Gretchen Freiheir Ridgeway (Box 14)
  - Ruth Kohorn Rosenberg (Class of 1976) interviewed by Milada Cook, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In her interview, Ruth Rosenberg remembers her time in Wilson House, working as house vice president, and Smith's social life. Rosenberg also talks about the transition from President Thomas Mendenhall to President Jill Kirk Conway, and student activism around the Vietnam War.
    - Video interview with Ruth Kohorn Rosenberg
    - Transcript of interview with Ruth Kohorn Rosenberg (Box 14)
  - Esther Rothblum (Class of 1976) interviewed by Sonia Lawrence, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Esther Rothblum talks about coming to Smith as an international student and learning how to be an American. Rothblum also reflects on her time at Smith as raising and engaging her feminist awareness. A clinical psychologist, Rothblum also reflects on what it was like to be a women pursuing a PhD in a male dominated field in the 80s.
    - Video interview with Esther Rothblum
    - Transcript of interview with Esther Rothblum (Box 14)
  - S. Mona Sinha (Class of 1988) interviewed by Rebecca York, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Mona Sinha talks about her introduction to Smith as a transfer student, including finding community in the International Student Preorientation program. She talks about the student group asking for divestment from South Africa, including a takeover of College Hall. As an Economics major, Sinha spent her junior year in the Picker Program in Washington. Since graduation Sinha has worked to inspire women's leadership education.
    - Video interview with S. Mona Sinha
    - Transcript of interview with S. Mona Sinha (Box 14)
  - Deborah Wess (Class of 1986) interviewed by Sonia Lawrence, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Deborah Wess reflects on Smith's political climate in the 80s. Wess talks about her involvement with a number of student-led activist groups on campus, including actions to divest from South Africa, and a "Love-In" to promote acceptance of LGBT members of the community.
    - Video interview with Deborah Wess
    - Transcript of interview with Deborah Wess (Box 14)
  - Serena M. Williams (Class of 1981) interviewed by Rebecca York, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Serena Williams remembers her introduction to Smith, focusing especially on the Bridge Program providing support to new students of color as an integral part of her Smith experience. Although she was an economy major, Williams recounts her experiences with racism on campus, as well as time spent building community amongst other women of color at the Mwangi Cultural Center. She also talks about her strong house community and favorite traditions, as well as her tenure as President of the Student Government Association.
    - Video interview with Serena M. Williams
    - Transcript of interview with Serena M. Williams (Box 14)
- Alumnae Oral History Project interviews (2017), Accession 2017-A-0144; 207 Gigabytes (Transcripts, video, and audio files)
  - Antonia Andreoli, class of 1967, interviewed by Hannah Schneider, 2017 May 19; Andreoli, Antonia; Schneider, Hannah; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Antonia Andreoli discusses her introduction to Smith and her experiences as a "scholarship kid". Andreoli talks about Parsons House traditions, socio-economic and racial tensions on campus, and the political nature of Smith in the Civil Rights Era. She reflects on her experiences working in Dining Services under her scholarship and how Smith allowed her to become "a strong woman who made her own life."
    This interview is available for research without restrictions
    Andreoli, Antonia
    - Video interview with Antonia Andreoli, 1 items (1 video )
    - Transcript of interview with Antonia Andreoli, 1 items (1 transcript)
  - Aracelis Biel (class of 2007) interviewed by Celeste Clerk, 2017 May 19; Biel, Aracelis; Clerk, Celeste; 1 oral histories (1 video and transcript)
    In this interview, Aracelis Biel talks about her introduction to Smith and her love of the Smith campus. As a four-year resident of Northrop house, Biel describes the social and political atmosphere of the Smith community during the mid-2000s, discussing issues like gender and the Bush years. She recalls her time as a Philosophy and English double major and the relationships she gained with both professors and administration.
    This interview is available for research without restrictions. Interview may not be placed online.
    Biel, Aracelis
    - Video interview with Aracelis Biel
    - Transcript of interview with Aracelis Biel
  - Interview with Barbara Blumenthal (Class of 1975) by Celeste Clerk, 2017 May 19; Blumenthal, Barbara; Clerk, Celeste; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Barbara Blumenthal talks about her relationship with the Rare Book Room at Smith as both a student and then later staff. Blumenthal reminisces about her beginnings in the book arts at Smith and how the staff in the Rare Book Room changed the course of her career. She recollects her time as a student in the 1970s and what it was like to be a married student on campus. At the end of the interview, Blumenthal talks about the changes to the library happening in 2017 and what it means to be connected to physical books in a digital age.
    This interview is available for research without restrictions.
    Blumenthal, Barbara
    - Video interview with Barbara Blumenthal
    - Transcript of interview with Barbara Blumenthal
  - Interview with Diana Clement (Class of 2007) by Hannah Schneider, 2017 May 20; Clement, Diana; Schneider, Hannah; 1 oral histories (Video and transcript)
    In this interview, Diana Clement describes her time on the Smith Rugby team and some of the traditions she loved from Morrow House. She remembers professors who gave her a start in the urban planning and landscape architect work she still does today. Clement also takes time to talk about the new technologies and social media coming about during her time at Smith and reflects on the confidence being at Smith has given her for the future. Clement gives this interview with her young child who cries every once in a while.
    Clement, Diana
    - Video of interview with Diana Clement
    - Transcript of interview with Diana Clement
  - Interview with Aneesha Gandhi (Class of 2007) by Illaria Dana, 2017 May 20; Gandhi, Aneesha; Dana, Illaria; 1 oral histories (Video and transcript)
    In this interview, Aneesha Gandhi remembers her first introduction to Smith and what the Cushing House community was like. Gandhi talks about how her junior year abroad in Spain helped her decide to double major in both Spanish and American Studies. She then talks about her life after Smith working in Boston at the labor and employment law firm Segal Roitman, and then going to Northeastern Law School and later becoming a supervising attorney at the National Immigrant Justice Center in Chicago with their LGBT project.
    Gandhi, Aneesha
    - Video interview with Aneesha Gandhi
    - Transcript of interview with Aneesha Gandhi
  - Interview with Vanessa Allen Henneke (Class of 1967) by Hannah Schneider, 2017 May 19; Henneke, Vanessa; Schneider, Hannah; 1 oral histories (Video and transcript)
    In this interview, Vanessa Allen Henneke recalls her time as a Southern girl coming to Smith. She talks about her Jordan House Mother and how community was built around the table at meals. Henneke remembers her time in the Russian a Capella choir and recalls the political atmosphere of Smith in the 1960s. She concludes with describing the work that she does today, and that the one thing she learned from Smith is to "just go out there and don't let any barriers stop you."
    Henneke, Vanessa
    - Video interview with Vanessa Allen Henneke
    - Transcript of interview with Vanessa Allen Henneke
  - Interview with Ileana Jiménez (Class of 1997) by Hannah Schneider, 2017 May 20; Jimenez, Ileana; Schneider, Hannah; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    This interview begins with Ileana Jiménez telling the story of how she came to Smith, her discovery of feminism, and what it was like to be a first generation college student from the Bronx. Jiménez remembers the political climate of the 90s, voting for Bill Clinton, Ellen coming out on TV, and protests led by Nosotras to support migrant farm worker in California. She also describes her involvement at Smith, how she tried to find a place to fit as a Puerto Rican queer woman and landed on student government. Jiménez's work after Smith began with a formative meeting with then Smith College President Ruth Simmons. She has worked the last 20 years teaching English and passing on her feminist teachings from Smith to the next generation of young women.
    Jimenez, Ileana
    - Video interview with Ileana Jiménez
    - Transcript of interview with Ileana Jiménez
  - Interview with Beverly Jones (Class of 1997) by Celeste Clerk, 2017 May 20; Jones, Beverly; Clerk, Celeste; 1 oral histories (Video and transcript)
    In this interview, Beverly Jones describes her path to Smith and her family's dedication to a liberal arts education. Jones remembers her time as a STRIDE scholar working in the Government Department, which she would end up majoring in. She talks about her time in both Chapin and Capen houses as well as about her time on the Smith Rugby team. Jones recalls the political atmosphere on campus and tells the story of how Smithies celebrated National Coming Out Day. The interview concludes with Jones describing the legal work that she now does for the ASPCA.
    Jones, Beverly
    - Video interview with Beverly Jones
    - Transcript of interview with Beverly Jones
  - Interview with Taeyun Kim (Class of 1997) by Illaria Dana, 2017 May 20; Kim, Taeyun; 1 oral histories (Video and transcript)
    In this interview, Taeyun Kim describes her involvement in the Smith community, namely with the Asian Student Alliance, the Korean American Students of Smith, and Gold Key. Kim also recalls her work with the local Amherst Evangelical Church including teaching English in Tanzania after graduation. As a Government major, Kim describes her experience in the Picker Program and classes that influenced her time at Smith. The interview concludes with Kim's reflection on her first time at a Smith reunion.
    Kim, Taeyun
    - Video interview with Taeyun Kim
    - Transcript of interview with Taeyun Kim
  - Interview with Jane McInerny (Class of 1978) by Hannah Schneider, 2017 May 19; McInerny, Class of 1978; Schneider, Hannah; 1 oral histories (video and transcript)
    McInerny, Class of 1978
    - Video interview with Jane McInerny
    - Transcript of interview with Jane McInerny
  - Interview with Mary C. Morgan (Class of 1967) by Celeste Clerk, 2017 May 20; Morgan, Mary; Clerk, Celeste; 1 oral histories
    In this interview, Mary C Morgan describes the serendipitous nature of her decision to come to Smith. She recalls discussions on Smith as an all-women's college and the formation of the Five College Consortium. Morgan then goes on to talk about her experience moving from an all-women's space to the male-dominated world of legal work. She discusses her work as both a lawyer and a judge and navigating that world as both a woman and a lesbian. The interview concludes with Morgan explaining that she "found that being a visible role model for people had impacts way beyond anything that I ever imagined or even intended. You never know when you drop a pebble in water what's going to happen."
    Morgan, Mary
    - Video interview with Mary C. Morgan
    - Transcript of interview with Mary C. Morgan
  - Interview with Amy Ellis Nutt (Class of 1977) by Hannah Schneider, 2017 May 19; Nutt, Class of 1977; Schneider, Hannah; 1 oral histories (Video and transcript)
    In this interview, Amy Ellis Nutt recalls the feminist nature of Smith as a women's college and how each student brings her own "sense of curiosity and intellectual rigor." She talks about the dating scene for queer women and the diversity of the Haven house community. Nutt then describes how Smith laid the groundwork for her future career. She talks about how, though interrupted by mental illness, her career has blossomed in the journalism world starting with Sports Illustrated and culminating in a Pulitzer Prize in 2011. The interview concludes with Nutt noting, "the storytelling that I won that award for began here because you learn how to tell stories in classes … what drives stories is a sense of mystery and a sense of curiosity and that was, that was the gift that Smith gave me."
    Nutt, Class of 1977
    - Video interview with Amy Ellis Nutt
    - Transcript of interview with Amy Ellis Nutt
  - Interview with Carol Chase Oppenheimer (Class of 1967) by Hannah Schneider, 2017 May 19; Oppenheimer, Carol; Schneider, Hannah; 1 oral histories (video and transcript)
    In this interview, Carol Chase Oppenheimer discusses her introductions to Smith both from the president of the college Mr. Mendenhall and speaker Betty Friedan who gave differing versions of what Smith would make a woman into. Oppenheimer recalls being politically active in the Northern Student Movement and the Amherst chapter of Students for a Democratic Society, working both for Haitian apple pickers as well as Smith housekeepers in union matters. She also describes her views on Vietnam protests and solidarity on campus and concludes the interview by talking about what it takes to be courageous both at Smith and in the world.
    Oppenheimer, Carol
    - Video interview with Carol Chase Oppenheimer
    - Transcript of interview with Carol Chase Oppenheimer
  - Interview Rachel Payne (Class of 1997) by Celeste Clerk, 2017 May 20; Payne, Rachel; Clerk, Celeste; 1 oral histories (video and transcript)
    In this interview, Rachel Payne discusses her introduction to Smith and how Smith feels now compared to her time here in the 1990s. She talks about her favorite professor and her experience defending her honors thesis as well as touching on what it was like being a financially independent student. Payne also recalls her time in both Morrow and Chase House as well as her time abroad in Japan with the Associated Kyoto Program. She talks about the transformative nature of Smith for her saying, "it was very empowering… And I think ultimately it isn't just the Smith education. It's being part of the Smith tradition and community that when you step out into the world, you have this whole institution behind you."
    Payne, Rachel
    - Video interview with Rachel Payne
    - Transcript of interview with Rachel Payne
  - Interview with Pipier Smith-Mumford (Class of 1978) by Illaria Dana, 2017 May 19; Smith-Mumford, Pipier; Dana, Illaria; 1 oral histories (video and transcript)
    In this interview, Pipier Smith-Mumford describes her experiences in Smith's Bridge Program, and the support networks she made at Smith. She recalls being active within the Black Student Alliance whose activism gave her the confidence to be truthful to herself and later on become a leader within her community. Smith-Mumford goes on to describe the work that she has done after Smith as a teacher and administrator in all levels of education. She emphasized the importance of community and focuses on how she can give back to the communities that have supported her.
    Smith-Mumford, Pipier
    - Video interview with Pipier Smith-Mumford
    - Transcript of interview with Pipier Smith-Mumford
  - Interview with Gail Van Ekeren (Class of 1967) by Illaria Dana, 2017 May 19; Van Ekeren, Gail; Dana, Illaria; 1 oral histories (video and transcript)
    In this interview, Gail Van Ekeren talks about her initial challenges coming to Smith and majoring in Physics. She remembers her house mother and how they would foster a sense of community and peace within the houses. Van Ekeren also recalls running the Goldwater campaign on campus and what it was like being Jewish at Smith. After her time at Smith, Van Ekeren explains, she has gone on to become a Physics teacher in Pennsylvania and was able to reconnect with a Smith professor in the Physics department through teaching conferences. The interview concludes with Van Ekeren explaining that she is now back in school taking classes in Anthropology and Archaeology, subjects she was introduced to by Smith.
    Van Ekeren, Gail
    - Video interview with Gail Van Ekeren
    - Transcript of interview with Gail Van Ekeren